## Leticia Vaz

# **Financial Operations Leader**

leticia.contatos@gmail.com

678-665-3897 • Atlanta, GA 30339

Accomplished professional with solid background in managing financial forecasting, process improvements, financial reporting, and closing processes. Recognized for talents in data analysis, business acuity, and big-picture vision. Creative problem-solver with a passion for resolving complex issues to influence positive revenue outcomes. Collaborative communicator continually focused on building relationships and promoting synergy across business lines and global units to drive positive change, cohesive, comprehensive business approaches, and enhanced profitability. *Areas of Expertise include:* 

- Strategic Planning & Forecasting
- Business Development
- Financial Reporting/Analysis
- Financial Solutions
- Relationship Building
- SSMS / MS Access

- Revenue & Profit Growth
- Project Management
- Financial Statements

## **Professional Experience**

## XCELERATION PARTNERS • Atlanta, Georgia • January 2019 to Present

#### FINANCE & OPERATIONS MANAGER

Deliver accurate and comprehensive financial information to executive management for long-term financial strategizing. Analyze operational and financial data to identify business insights and opportunities for process improvement.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Manage all financial close processes and procedures, ensuring timely monthly close processing and presenting financial month-end package to executive team.
- Analyze profit and loss (P&L) to determine impact of each general ledger account and provide insights into overall health of business.
- Work closely with Payroll and HR teams to manage expenses related to 401(k) contributions as well as health and welfare benefits, monitoring costs in relation to budgeted amounts.

## XCELERATION PARTNERS • Atlanta, Georgia • June 2017 to January 2019

#### SR. FINANCIAL ANALYST

Provided robust modeling and reporting to facilitate executive-level decision making. Developed detailed spreadsheets to identify trends and develop forecasts. Consolidated and analyzed monthly results, exchange rate fluctuation, and cost of living (COLA) impact.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Designed and implemented automated processes, eliminating manual procedures to increase productivity and improve flow of information throughout organization.
- Managed fund accounts for domestic and international customers, verifying product pricing across different currencies and analyzing fluctuation in exchange rates.
- Conducted month-end closing, preparing journal entries, reconciling general ledger and bank statements, and producing intercompany financial reports.
- Partnered with fulfillment team and SQL analysts on timely processing of product mark-ups, ensuring updates posted correctly to database.

## PNC BANK • Atlanta, Georgia • March 2016 to June 2017

### FINANCIAL CONSULTANT

Create and analyze client reports, identify opportunities, and implement optimal financial solutions to current and potential customers. Meet with customers to gain an understanding of their financial situation, assess needs, and provide advice to meet their goals. Set up accounts, initiate loan applications, and other administrative duties.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Support strategic decision making by developing an automated waterfall chart that compiles and measures monthly performance indicators for metro Atlanta locations.
- Establish a customer forecast model that estimates future revenues and costs by leveraging historical trends and data.

Continued...

Provide outstanding service to ensure optimal financial outcomes for clients and repeat business in the future.

## DUN & BRADSTREET • São Paulo, Brazil • March 2010 to August 2013

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Developed financial and business solutions by defining, analyzing, and documenting research. Leveraged Oracle systems to create and analyze data while consulting business principals with risk management, credit, and marketing solutions. Managed credit analysis and pre-analysis of balance sheets. Assigned Dun & Bradstreet ratings to North American, Central American, and South American companies by analyzing principal financial statements. Researched commercial trade references to evaluate credit behavior and consulted with government agencies as needed.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Aided in effective decision making by assessing the financial situation of companies prior to potential merger or acquisition.
- Ensured client needs were met by communicating clearly and effectively with internal/external customers and suppliers.
- Increased sales and response rate by investigation and analysis of the most potential clients.

## **Internship Experience**

### MAKSOUD PLAZA • São Paulo, Brazil • 2009 to 2010

#### **ACCOUNTING INTERN**

Collected sales reports and reconciled them against the system. Maintained bank accounts and financial balance sheets, reporting findings back to the accounting department. Updated weekly and monthly finance reports.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

Recognized for accurate and thorough financial reporting and analysis abilities.

CRESCER • São Paulo, Brazil • 2008 to 2009

### FINANCE/HR INTERN

Supported the Finance and Human Resources departments in daily activities. Assisted the HR department in identifying candidates, scheduling interviews, and maintaining accounts. Calculated work hours and assisted with payroll in the Finance department. Maintained and monitored office, classroom, and student budget and expenses.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

• Earned a reputation for quality and consistency as well as willingness to take on outside projects and assignments.

# **Education & Training**

#### Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (Focus in Finance)

PAULISTA UNIVERSITY | São Paulo, Brazil | 2013

#### Certification - Data Science bootcamp

GEORGIA TECH | ATLANTA, GA | 2020

Georgia Tech Data Science and Analytics Boot Camp is a fast-paced, dynamic program that covers the specialized skills for the booming field of data, including Advanced VBA Scripting, Modeling, Forecasting, Python, Pandas, Tableau, Big Data Analytics, Machine Leaning, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, API Interactions, Social Media Mining, SQL, Tableau, Advanced Statistics, Machine Learning, R, Git/GitHub, and more.

NMLS Mortgage License, 2016

Cultural Exchange Program, 2013 to 2015

Languages: English, Portuguese, & Spanish